Andrés Reyes

Core Skill:

Scrum Master

Industry Verticals:

Advertising Media Banking Technology

Tools & Techniques:

Agile Scrum SAFe Waterfall

Summary:

With over a decade in software development I'm no less excited about building excellent teams and delivering high value software. My goal is to work with cross department, with multicultural teams since I enjoy collaborating with people. My native curiosity helps me to smoothly plugin into multiple projects from various industries (News and video on demand platforms), Fast Moving Consumer Goods, Banking, and Finance). I'm passionate about Agile and how this can transform and develop digital teams. • Result-orientated with skills and abilities enhanced by the various project areas: • Strong analytical thinking, eager to learn, and enjoy working with people. · Able to adapt to different environments and vast experience of working with distributed agile teams, across multicultural enviro

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

Master's degree, "European Studies and Community Law, Bucharest University, 2007

Certifications:

PSM I, Scrum.org, 2024 Prince2 Agile, Scrum Agile Institute, 2020 ITIL, AXELOS, SAFe 5.1, SAFE,

Spoken Languages:

English, C1

Soft Skills:

Accountability
Active listening
Coaching
Collaboration
Self-Awarenes
Self-learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Banking

Scrum Master

2022-12-01 - 2024-01-01

Project descriptions:

Project: Payments - B2B (Implementation of a new payments application) Period: December 2022 – January 2024 Role: Scrum Master Development Context: Agile Project Delivery based on Scrum. Scrum Master for two teams, the same team shape for both teams – 4 Java developers and 3 testers (manual and automation).

Responsibilities:

Tasks/Experience: • Keeping the teams organized, on track, and focused on what and how the work should be delivered. • Encourage, support, and guide continuous improvement of the teams, their products, and processes. • Helping the teams focus on creating high-value Increments that meet the Definition of Done. • Removing blockers and helping teams to achieve their commitments (identifying risks, impediments, dependencies, and other issues, and facilitating quick resolutions. • Facilitating the development team to work on the day-to-day activities. • Ensuring the backlog readiness (Sprints backlog meets the Definition of Ready). • Facilitate agile activities and meetings, including sprint planning, retrospectives, and sprint reviews. • Streamline communication within teams, external stakeholders, and management. Achievements: Keeping a high Team Morale level for teams. Reaching and maintaining a good velocity metric. PROJECTS WITH PREVIOUS EMPLOYERS - PRO TV Project: News & Content Applications (Media & Entertainment) Period: August 2018 - November 2022 Role: Scrum Master/Project Manager Development Context: Agile Project Delivery based on Scrum and Kanban. Scrum Master/Project Manager for one team- 6 PHP developers, 5 Frontend developers, one Art Director, and one Analytics & SEO Specialist. Technology Stack: Jira, Confluence, Miro Board Tasks/Experience: • Keeping the team organized, on track, and focused on what and how the work should be delivered. • Encourage. support, and guide continuous improvement of the team. • Helping the team focus on creating high-value Increments that meet the Definition of Done. Removing blockers and helping teams to achieve their commitments (identifying risks, impediments, dependencies, and other issues, and facilitating quick resolutions. • Facilitating the development team to work on the day-to-day activities. • Ensuring the backlog readiness (Sprints backlog meets the Definition of Ready). • Facilitate agile activities

Programming	Languages:
-------------	------------

Java

Tools & Techniques:

Testing:

Agile, Jira, Miro, Scrum

Automation Testing, Manual Testing, Unit Testing